RYAN J. TRAPP

ryantrapp@gmail.com

Bozeman, MT • 406-580-0641

PROFILE

Strategic technical solution sales professional, with demonstrated experience helping organizations throughout many industries better meet the needs of their customer base while improving the internal efficiencies of their support environment to drive down costs while improving customer satisfaction, acquisition and retention.

Qualifications include:

- Demonstrated leadership in high-pressure day-to-day team operations to provide a high level of service to customers
- Strategic analyst and consultant, with intimate exposure in the areas of CRM and call center technology, including customer self service, support ticketing, workflow, network and telephony systems, and customer analytics
- Extensive communication with small business owners, all the way to Fortune 500 C-level executives, on topics ranging from marketing/outreach activities to service environments and IT infrastructure
- Experience helping large organizations discover weaknesses in their service environment using a variety of methods, including "support audits" and on-site call center observation through ride-alongs with customer service representatives and workflow documentation
- Technical understanding across varied environments including both client-side and server-side operations

EXPERIENCE

ORACLE - Bozeman, MT

Senior Solutions Consultant

September 2012 – Present

- Experience leading account strategy, customer/prospect discovery, value proposition, product demonstration, technical fit, and pricing within the sales opportunity process
- Responsible for understanding prospect/customer's requirements and how they relate to business need through
 discovery as well as on-site observation in order to develop a specific, highly configured product demonstration
 for the line of business stakeholders; focused on customer acquisition, retention, and operational efficiency
- Contributed to over \$2M in closed new business (recurring revenue) with new logos in multiple industries throughout tenure at Oracle
- Fluent in customer service, business intelligence, help desk, call center, APIs, ecommerce, SEO, SaaS, mobile and social CRM
- Lead multiple, intensive two-week training courses in San Francisco, CA and Bozeman, MT; while documenting product information and process docs, for new-hires to the Oracle Service Cloud product suite
- Part of a small team that leveraged the existing Oracle Service Cloud solution to create an internal searchable knowledge base of sales and product related content to assist legacy Oracle employees in learning about the Oracle Service Cloud Suite
- Provided over 100 highly customized demos during tenure with Oracle across the Oracle CX suite of products including: Oracle Service Cloud, Engagement Cloud and Policy Automation
- Lead on-site discovery and presentation sessions with closed deals at companies such as Sephora, Medline,
 Orbitz, FICO, as well as many others
- Presented internal and external webinars to hundreds of employees and customers across topics such as driving
 increases in customer satisfaction, automating internal policies, and ways to better meet customers where and
 when they want to interact
- Regarded as an expert in the Oracle Policy Automation tool.

RIGHTNOW (ACQUIRED BY ORACLE)

September 2009 – September 2012

Sales

- Lead all Client Expansion in total new opportunities in 2010
- Highest "Closed New + Expansion" for new opportunities in 2010 at over \$650K
- Provided high-level product walk-throughs to prospects when necessary to drive interest and next steps

• Demonstrated success speaking with every level of title (C-level, V-level, etc.) in areas such as Operations, Customer Support, IT, Marketing, and Finance.

KANA SOFTWARE - Bozeman, MT

March 2007 - April 2009

Inside Sales

- Developed projects to expand product suite with 6 current customers
- Helped to resolve existing customer issues
- Leveraged my current customer contacts to identify new opportunities within my current customer's organization, helping to expand our current product usage and solve a larger share of the customer's needs
- Worked aggressively, utilizing all business tools available, to succeed under a sales quota of \$4 Million
- Directed a team of technical and professional services individuals during the sales process

PRINTINGFORLESS.COM - Livingston, MT

May 2003 – March 2007

Production Coordinator and Technical Service Representative

- Effectively managed the workflow through the production department; observing, tracking and driving department's performance goals by managing inputs (TSR's) and outputs (printing press load)
- Contributed to three consecutive record quarters for total production revenue through increased efficiency
- Helped implement the production team system, bringing in elements gained from my tenure leading a \$2 million dollar per year Technical Service team
- Responsible for the acquisition of new customers, growing existing customer accounts, management of customer's print orders from start to completion; file and marketing consultation, digital file manipulation, and hightouch customer service
- Implemented a new three-person TSR team and acted as Team Lead

EDUCATION

Montana State University – Bozeman, MT B.S. – Business Marketing

Oregon State University – Online Currently pursuing B.S. in Computer Science (planned completion Spring 2020)